Guide to the Jewish Labor Committee Records, Part III WAG.025.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Operations and Subject Files, 1903-2007
  - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC): Plenum, 1985; 1 folder (Box 475)
  - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC): Plenary, 1989; 1 folder (Box 475)
  - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC): Plenum, 1993; 1 folder (Box 475)
  - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC): Plenary Sessions, 1995, 1997; 1 folder (Box 475)
  - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC): Program Plan, 1973-1974; 2 folders (Box 475)
  - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC): Program Plan (Affirmative Action Statement with Our Revisions), 1974-1975; 1 folder (Box 475)
  - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC): Progress Report, 1975; 1 folder (Box 475)
  - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC): Quotas, 1981; 1 folder (Box 475)
  - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC): Reassessment Conference-- Public Schools and American Democratic Pluralism, 1971; 1 folder (Box 476)
  - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC): "Right to Work" Opposition, 1979; 1 folder (Box 476)
  - National Community Relations Advisory Council (NCRAC): St. Louis, 1962-1963; 1 folder (Box 476)
  - National Community Relations Advisory Council (NCRAC): Subcommittee on Interfaith Activities, 1946; 1 folder (Box 476)
  - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC): Task Force: Trade Union Project, 1974; 1 folder (Box 476)
  - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC): Tax Exemption Questions, 1973; 1 folder (Box 476)
  - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC): Welfare Reform, 1994; 1 folder (Box 476)
  - Jewish Council for Public Affairs (JCPA), 1998, 2005; 2 folders (Box 476)
  - National Yiddish Book Center, 1995-1997, undated; 3 folders (Box 448)
  - New Jewish Agenda, 1981-1991, undated; 2 folders (Box 448)
  - National Trade Union Council (NTUC), 1956, 1965, 1984-1997; 11 folders (Box 449)
  - New York State Legislature, 1979-1983, undated; 2 folders (Box 449)
  - News Clippings re: Labor and Various Topics, circa 1930-1979, 1989-1999; 3 folders (Box 489)
  - News Articles: General, 1994-1996; 2 folders (Box 460)
  - News Articles and Press Releases: JLC, 1985-1991, 1997-1998; 3 folders (Box 460)
  - JLC New York Legislative Committee, 1974, 1979-1983, 1985-1988, undated; 2 folders (Box 449)
  - JLC New York Legislative Committee: Conferences, Proposals, and Subject Files, 1952, 1976-1986, undated; 29 folders (Box 476)
  - New York City and New York State Issues and Organizations, 1981-1982, 1991-1996, undated; 10 folders (Box 449)
  - Neo-Nazism and European Relations, 1976, 1978; 1 folder (Box 449)
  - Northeast Economic Development, 1976-1980, undated; 1 folder (Box 449)
  - Nicaragua, 1982-1983; 1 folder (Box 449)
  - 92nd Street Y, 1994; 1 folder (Box 449)
  - Ocean Hill-Brownsville, circa 1968; 1 folder (Box 449)
  - Occupational Safety and Health Act (OSHA), 1994; 1 folder (Box 449)
  - Office and Professional Employees International Union (OPEIU), Local 153, 1951-1953, 1957-1973; 3 folders (Box 472)
  - Organizations Represented at 1934 JLC Convention (Card Files, Unoriginal), undated (Box 522)
  - Orthodox Jewish Home, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 449)
  - Subject Files: "P", 1947, 1965-1967, 1974-1988, 1993-1997, 2002-2004, undated; 33 folders (Box 449)
  - Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO), 1974, 1978-1990, undated; 4 folders (Box 449)
  - Perry, Michael, 1983, 1987-1988, 1993-1997, undated; 7 folders (Box 449)
  - Persons Rescued by the JLC, 1940-1941; 1 folder (Box 449)
  - Committee for Public Education and Religious Liberty (PEARL), 1980-1983; 1 folder (Box 449)
  - Photographs and Printed Ephemera: JLC Conventions (1975-1993), Educators' Chapter, National Trade Union Council Labor Human Rights Dinners (1967-1989), and General JLC Staff and Events, 1903-2004, undated (Box 430)
  - Harlan Baker/Professor Hanson of Maine (Labor Education Project), 1986-1990, undated; 1 folder (Box 430)
  - Pittston, 1989; 1 folder (Box 449)
  - Plant Closings, 1984-1993; 4 folders (Box 450)
  - Poland, 1980-1983, 1989, 1993-1997, 2000, undated; 24 folders (Box 450)
  - Pony Express, 1993-1995; 1 folder (Box 450)
  - JLC Programs, 1969, 1980-1985, 1990-1994; 6 folders (Box 450)
  - JLC Press and Publicity, 1948-1967, 1973-1975, 1979-1982, 1987-1997; 9 folders (Box 450)
  - Quincy Farms Mushrooms, 1995-1996; 1 folder (Box 450)
  - Racism/Race Relations, 1947, 1959, 1984, undated; 3 folders (Box 450)
  - A. Phillip Randolph, 1975-1976, 1983, 1986, undated; 3 folders (Box 450)
  - Itzhak Rabin, 1995-1996; 1 folder (Box 450)
  - Rabbis, 1993-1996; 2 folders (Box 450)
  - Subject Files: "R", 1977-1986, 1991-1997, 2001-2004, undated; 20 folders (Box 451)
  - Raleigh Conference (JLC), 1985; 1 folder (Box 451)
  - Reagan Budget, 1981-1983, undated; 4 folders (Box 451)
  - Refugees, 1977-1983, undated; 2 folders (Box 451)
  - Refugees Rescued by the JLC (Card Files), circa 1940-1949 (Box 522)
  - Resolutions (JLC), 1982, 1986, 1988, 1990, 1993; 5 folders (Box 451)
  - Right-Wing Material, circa 1930-1969; 3 folders (Box 489)
  - Rustin, Baynard, 1966, 1975, 1977, 1983, 1987, undated; 2 folders (Box 451)
  - Subject Files: "Sa" — "So", 1949, 1958, 1973-2000, 2004, undated; 35 folders (Box 451)
  - Save Our Port/Assemblyman Koppell's Hearing on Waterfront Development, 1983; 2 folders (Box 451)
  - Second Avenue Deli, 1995-1996; 4 folders (Box 451)
  - Shanker, Al, 1985, 1993, 1997, 2007; 1 folder (Box 451)
  - Sheinkman, Jacob, 1975-1980; 1 folder (Box 485)
  - Slaiman, Donald Correspondence, 1979-1983; 3 folders (Box 485)
  - Social Democrats, 1980-1981, 1987; 3 folders (Box 438)
  - Social and Economic Issues Commission, 1977-1981, undated; 5 folders (Box 438)
  - Social Security, 1981-1983, undated; 3 folders (Box 438)
  - Socialist International, 1978-1983, undated; 5 folders (Box 438)
  - Socialist Party, 1972, 1982-1983; 1 folder (Box 438)
  - Socialism, 1989; 1 folder (Box 438)
  - Solidarity Day, 1981, 1991; 2 folders (Box 438)
  - South Africa, 1976, 1979-1988, undated; 6 folders (Box 438)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1970, 1976-1989, undated; 25 folders (Box 438)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1961-1989 (Box 424)
  - Soviet Refugees, 1978, 1987; 2 folders (Box 438)
  - Soviet Union/Soviet Life, 1986, 1989-1991, undated; 3 folders (Box 438)
  - JP Stevens Boycott, 1974-1985, undated; 20 folders (Box 452)
  - Sweatshops, 1994-2000, undated; 3 folders (Box 452)
  - Staff Meeting (JLC), 1986-1988; 1 folder (Box 452)
  - Subject Files: "Sp" — "Sy", 1982-1985, 1989-1996, undated; 15 folders (Box 453)
  - Strategic Planning (JLC), 1993-1997, undated; 5 folders (Box 453)
  - Strawberry Workers, 1996-1998; 2 folders (Box 453)
  - Subject Files: "T", 1966-1969, 1976-2003, undated (Box 453)
  - Subject Files: "U", 1969, 1976-1987, 1991-2000, 2006-2007; 20 folders (Box 454)
  - Undocumented Aliens, 1975-1981, 1993; 3 folders (Box 454)
  - Unemployment, 1975, 1978, 1980, undated; 3 folders (Box 454)
  - United Farm Workers, 1968-1975, 1979-1985; 6 folders (Box 454)
  - United Jewish Appeal (UJA)-Federation of New York: Directory, 1995; 1 folder (Box 454)
  - United Jewish Communities, 1995-2001; 2 folders (Box 454)
  - United Nations, 1980, 1992, 1997; 4 folders (Box 454)
  - United States Holocaust Memorial Museum/Council, 1989, 1993-1994, 1997-2000; 4 folders (Box 454)
  - United States Trade Representative (USTR), 1988; 1 folder (Box 454)
  - Urban Enterprise Zones, 1981-1982, undated; 1 folder (Box 454)
  - Subject Files: "V", 1999-2000; 2 folders (Box 454)
  - Voting Rights Legislation, 1981-1982; 2 folders (Box 454)
  - Vouchers: School, 1997-2005, undated; 4 folders (Box 454)
  - Subject Files: "W", 1970, 1987-1999, 2007; 14 folders (Box 454)
  - Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, 1984-1998, 2004; 3 folders (Box 455)
  - Waldheim, Kurt, 1986-1989; 1 folder (Box 455)
  - War Crimes Commission: United Nations Files, 1986-1987; 1 folder (Box 455)
  - Warsaw Ghetto, 1943, 1951-1968, 1972-1981, 1990, 1997-2008, undated; 3 folders (Box 439)
  - Warsaw Ghetto: Anniversaries, 1983, 1989-1993; 3 folders (Box 439)
  - Warsaw Ghetto: Clippings and Press, 1979, 1983-1988, undated; 2 folders (Box 439)
  - Warsaw Ghetto: Notes/Background Material, 1946, 1962, 1977-1984, undated; 3 folders (Box 439)
  - Warsaw Ghetto: Source Material, 1981-1983; 2 folders (Box 439)
  - Warsaw Ghetto: Final, 1972, 1977, 1983, undated; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - Warsaw Ghetto: Treblinka, 1943, undated; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - Warsaw Ghetto Resistance Organization, 1981, 1989; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - Polish Government and Warsaw Ghetto Memorial, circa 1983; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - Weber Case [United Steelworkers v. Weber], 1979; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - West Bank Settlements, 1979, 1983; 2 folders (Box 455)
  - West Germany, Nikolaus Simon, 1978; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - Women in Labor, 1980; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - Work Sharing, 1981; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - Workers Defense League, 1978, 1982-1983, 1987, 1993; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - Workers Under Communism Limited Series (Four Journals), 1982-1984; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - Workmen's Circle, 1972, 1981, 1983, 1995-2002; 2 folders (Box 439)
  - Workmen's Circle Division: Labels and Outgoing Letters, 1962, 1965, 1978-1984, 1988, 1995-1999; 3 folders (Box 455)
  - Workplace Fairness Bill, 1988-2000; 1 folder (Box 455)
  - World Labor Athletic Carnival, 1936, 1985, 1992, undated; 1 folder (Box 455)
  - World Zionist Congress: Draft Resolution on Israel, 1982; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - Subject Files: "Y", 1941-1942, 1964-1965, 1997-2001, undated; 5 folders (Box 455)
  - Subject Files: "Y", 1969, 1979-1987, 1992-1993; 5 folders (Box 439)
  - Andrew Young Affair, 1979; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - Andrew Young/Palestine Liberation Organization/Black-Jewish, 1979; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - International Youth Conference, 1985; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - Youth Institute for Peace in the Middle East, 1977-1978, 1982-1983, 1987, undated; 2 folders (Box 439)
  - Zaire, 1977; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - Zionism, 1988; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - American Zionist Youth Foundation, undated; 1 folder (Box 439)
  - Dennis Zensen/United Farm Workers/Sylvan, Inc. [and World Jewish Congress], 1985, 1995, 2001, 2005; 1 folder (Box 455)
  - Zuckerman, Jacob: Speeches and Writings, 1946-1955; 2 folders (Box 455)
  - Taylor, Betty Kaye Correspondence (Chronological Files), 1973-1982; 17 folders (Box 484)
  - Wronker, Linda Chronological and Correspondence Files, 1977-1983; 6 folders (Box 485)
  - Buttons (mostly Political), circa 1980-1999; 7 items (Box 507)
  - Massachusetts Tributes and Resolutions (Oversize), 1954, 1987; 1 folder (Box 507)
  - Poster re: Palestine (Arabic), 1989; 1 folder (Box 507)
  - JLC Centre Medem Exposition Poster, undated; 1 folder (Box 507)
  - News Articles (Oversize), 1938-1945; 1 folder (Box 507)
  - Daily Forward Article on Baruch Charney Vladeck, undated; 1 folder (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS002)
- Series III: Officers and Staff Members, 1939-2008
  This series into divided into several subseries containing the files of various JLC officers and staff members. The contents reflect the areas of special interest or expertise of each individual.
  Materials within each subseries are arranged alphabetically unless otherwise noted.
  - Subseries A: Lasar Epstein, 1952-1970
    Historical/Biographical Note
    Lasar Epstein worked in China for twenty years as a representative of the Jewish Labor Bund. During World War II, he coordinated the distribution of aid to European Jews who took refuge in Shanghai. After the war, he moved his family to the United States, where he would join the JLC staff.
    The papers of Lasar Epstein are largely concerned with aid to overseas refugees and the JLC's attempts to assist Jewish families in locating their relatives in the aftermath of World War II.
    - Activities (Lasar Epstein), Undated (Box 221, Folder 1)
    - Affidavits, 1956-1961 (Box 221, Folder 2)
    - Aid: Clothing, 1959-1961 (Box 221, Folder 3)
    - Aid: General, 1957-1966 (Box 221, Folder 4)
    - Akron, OH, 1960-1966 (Box 221, Folder 5)
    - Alabama, 1966 (Box 221, Folder 6)
    - Albany, NY, 1958-1965 (Box 221, Folder 7)
    - Albert Company, 1959-1960 (Box 221, Folder 8)
    - Alebarda, David, 1962 (Box 221, Folder 9)
    - American Council for Nationalities Service, 1962 (Box 221, Folder 10)
    - American Federation of Jews from Central Europe, 1965 (Box 221, Folder 11)
    - American Jewish Committee, 1965-1967 (Box 221, Folder 12)
    - American Jewish Congress, 1958-1960 (Box 221, Folder 13)
    - American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee, 1957-1967 (Box 221, Folder 14-15)
    - American Red Cross, 1962 (Box 221, Folder 16)
    - American Zionist Council, 1959 (Box 221, Folder 17)
    - Anti-Semitism, 1965 (Box 221, Folder 18)
    - Appel, Bronislaw, Dr. (Poland), 1961-1965 (Box 221, Folder 19)
    - Argentina, 1957-1967 (Box 221, Folder 20)
    - Argentina: Lipski, I, 1963-1964 (Box 221, Folder 21)
    - Arkansas, 1959 (Box 221, Folder 22)
    - Atlanta, GA, 1957-1965 (Box 221, Folder 23)
    - Aufbau, 1958-1963 (Box 221, Folder 24)
    - Austria, 1956-1964 (Box 221, Folder 25)
    - Australia, 1956-1967 (Box 221, Folder 26)
    - Baltimore, MD, 1957-1967 (Box 221, Folder 27)
    - Belgium, 1954-1959 (Box 221, Folder 28)
    - Belgium: Child Adoption Department, 1964-1966 (Box 221, Folder 29)
    - Black Fund, 1959 (Box 221, Folder 30)
    - Blatman Family, 1955-1959 (Box 221, Folder 31)
    - Boksenbojm, Mojsze, 1957-1962 (Box 221, Folder 32)
    - Books (Donated), 1956-1967 (Box 221, Folder 33)
    - Boston, MA, 1958-1962 (Box 221, Folder 34)
    - Brazil, 1957-1966 (Box 221, Folder 35)
    - Bridgeport, CT, 1964 (Box 221, Folder 36)
    - Brockton, MA, 1962 (Box 221, Folder 37)
    - Brookline, MA, 1962-1964 (Box 221, Folder 38)
    - Buffalo, NY, 1958-1962 (Box 221, Folder 39)
    - Camden, NJ, 1958-1964 (Box 221, Folder 40)
    - Canton, OH, 1962 (Box 221, Folder 41)
    - Cooperative for American Relief Everywhere (CARE, Inc.), 1957-1962 (Box 221, Folder 42-45)
    - Cooperative for American Relief Everywhere (CARE, Inc.), 1963-1968 (Box 222, Folder 1-3)
    - Certified Movers, 1961 (Box 222, Folder 4)
    - Charney, Daniel: Book Fund, 1960-1962 (Box 222, Folder 5)
    - Chattanooga, TN, 1957-1959 (Box 222, Folder 6)
    - Chelsea, MA, 1964-1967 (Box 222, Folder 7)
    - Chicago, IL, 1957-1967 (Box 222, Folder 8)
    - Chile, 1960-1964 (Box 222, Folder 9)
    - China, 1959 (Box 222, Folder 10)
    - Cincinnati, OH, 1957-1964 (Box 222, Folder 11)
    - Civil Rights, 1957 (Box 222, Folder 12)
    - Claims Conference, 1958-1964 (Box 222, Folder 13-14)
    - Cleveland, OH, 1958-1967 (Box 222, Folder 15)
    - Cloak Joint Board Chapter (Women's Division), 1967 (Box 222, Folder 16)
    - Club Yiddish, 1958 (Box 222, Folder 17)
    - Colombia, 1957-1958 (Box 222, Folder 18)
    - Columbus, OH, 1958-1959 (Box 222, Folder 19)
    - Common Council for American Unity, 1959 (Box 222, Folder 20)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims, 1956-1960 (Box 222, Folder 21)
    - Conference of Presidents, 1966-1967 (Box 222, Folder 22)
    - Contributions, 1958-1967 (Box 222, Folder 23-26)
    - Contributions: Carpenters Cooperative, Israel, 1960-1961 (Box 222, Folder 27)
    - Contributions: Israeli Children, 1958-1961 (Box 222, Folder 28)
    - Contributions: Roumanian Jews, 1959 (Box 222, Folder 29)
    - Contributions: Yiddish Schools, Israel, 1967 (Box 222, Folder 30)
    - Convention, 1965 (Box 222, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1965 (Box 222, Folder 32-39)
    - Correspondence: A — F, 1955-1968 (Box 223)
    - Correspondence: F — J, 1956-1967 (Box 224)
    - Correspondence: K — L, 1956-1967 (Box 225)
    - Correspondence: M — P, 1956-1967 (Box 226)
    - Correspondence: R — S, 1956-1968 (Box 227)
    - Correspondence: S — Y, 1956-1966 (Box 228)
    - Correspondence: Z, 1956-1966 (Box 229, Folder 1-4)
    - Costa Rica, 1961 (Box 229, Folder 5)
    - Council Bluffs, IA, 1959 (Box 229, Folder 6)
    - Crane, Syma, 1967 (Box 229, Folder 6a)
    - Crank Letters, 1959 (Box 229, Folder 7)
    - Cuba, 1958-1961 (Box 229, Folder 8)
    - CYCO (Central Yiddish Cultural Organization), 1958 (Box 229, Folder 9)
    - Czechoslovakia, 1958 (Box 229, Folder 10)
    - Dachau: International Committee, 1965 (Box 229, Folder 11)
    - Davenport, IA, 1960 (Box 229, Folder 12)
    - Dawidowicz, Mateusz, 1959 (Box 229, Folder 13)
    - Dayton, OH, 1963-1964 (Box 229, Folder 14)
    - Deascan, 1959-1967 (Box 229, Folder 15)
    - Denmark, 1957-1961 (Box 229, Folder 16)
    - Denver, CO, 1957-1962 (Box 229, Folder 17)
    - Detroit, MI, 1957-1967 (Box 229, Folder 18)
    - Divagando (Italian Weekly Magazine), 1959 (Box 229, Folder 19)
    - Dorchester, MA, 1957-1961 (Box 229, Folder 20)
    - Dues, 1957-1967 (Box 229, Folder 21-25)
    - Eisenbach Case, 1952-1964 (Box 229, Folder 26)
    - El Paso, TX, 1958 (Box 229, Folder 27)
    - Employment, 1955-1967 (Box 229, Folder 28-30)
    - England, 1957-1970 (Box 229, Folder 31)
    - England, 1947-1948, 1956; 1 folder (Box 492)
    - Epstein, Lasar, 1962-1964 (Box 229, Folder 32-33)
    - Figa Fund, 1960-1962 (Box 229, Folder 34)
    - Flint, MI, 1965 (Box 229, Folder 35)
    - France, 1957-1967 (Box 229, Folder 36-38)
    - Froyen Central, 1959-1967 (Box 229, Folder 39)
    - Galveston, TX, 1958-1959 (Box 229, Folder 40)
    - Gary, IN, 1957-1958 (Box 229, Folder 41)
    - Germany, 1957-1967 (Box 229, Folder 42)
    - Gleichman, Shimon, 1962 (Box 229, Folder 43)
    - Goldman, Paul, 1958 (Box 229, Folder 44)
    - Grabski, David, 1963-1964 (Box 229, Folder 45)
    - Graebe, Matter, 1961 (Box 229, Folder 46)
    - Grajner, Michal, 1957-1963 (Box 229, Folder 47)
    - Grand Rapids, MI, 1956-1961 (Box 229, Folder 48)
    - Hammond, IN, 1959-1967 (Box 229, Folder 49)
    - Hartford, CT, 1957-1958 (Box 229, Folder 50)
    - Haverhill, MA, 1959 (Box 229, Folder 51)
    - Hebrew Immigrant Aid Society (HIAS), 1956-April 1958 (Box 229, Folder 52-53)
    - Hebrew Immigrant Aid Society (HIAS), May 1958-1967 (Box 230, Folder 1-4)
    - Holland, 1963 (Box 230, Folder 5)
    - Honduras, 1957 (Box 230, Folder 6)
    - Houston, TX, 1958-1967 (Box 230, Folder 7)
    - Hungarian Jews, 1957 (Box 230, Folder 8)
    - Hungarian Refugees, 1958 (Box 230, Folder 9)
    - Igla, Joseph and Rachel, 1964-1966 (Box 230, Folder 10-11)
    - Immigration, 1957-1962 (Box 230, Folder 12-13)
    - Immigration and Citizenship Conference, 1963-1967 (Box 230, Folder 14-18)
    - Immigration Problems, 1956-1959 (Box 230, Folder 19)
    - Indianapolis, IN, 1958 (Box 230, Folder 20)
    - International Ladies Garment Workers Union, 1960 (Box 230, Folder 21)
    - International Rescue Committee, 1957-1966 (Box 230, Folder 22)
    - Israel, 1956-1965 (Box 230, Folder 23-30)
    - Israel, 1966 (Box 231, Folder 1)
    - Israel: Aid, 1955-1967 (Box 231, Folder 2-5)
    - Israel: Beersheba Library, 1962 (Box 231, Folder 6)
    - Israel: Books, 1958-1959 (Box 231, Folder 7)
    - Israel: Books, 1952-1956; 2 folders (Box 492)
    - Israel: Books (United States Information Agency), 1957-1958 (Box 231, Folder 9)
    - Israel: Brith Avodah, 1967 (Box 231, Folder 10)
    - Israel: Children's Home, 1965 (Box 231, Folder 11)
    - Israel: Clothing, 1966 (Box 231, Folder 12)
    - Israel: Cooperatives, 1957-1963 (Box 231, Folder 13)
    - Israel: Eliezer Steinberg Library, 1960 (Box 231, Folder 14)
    - Israel: Hebrew University Microfilm Project, 1960-1962 (Box 231, Folder 15)
    - Israel: Kursky Library, 1955-1967 (Box 231, Folder 16-17)
    - Israel: Libraries, 1957-1958 (Box 231, Folder 18)
    - Israel: New Arrivals, 1957 (Box 231, Folder 19)
    - Israel: Parcels (Children), 1958-1960 (Box 231, Folder 20)
    - Israel: Peretz Library, 1955-1967 (Box 231, Folder 21)
    - Israel: Printers Home, 1955-1956 (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - Israel: Special Emergency Campaign, 1967 (Box 231, Folder 23)
    - Israel: Yiddish Schools, 1964-1966 (Box 231, Folder 24)
    - Israel: Zygielbojm Auditorium, 1957-1958 (Box 231, Folder 25)
    - Italy, 1957 (Box 231, Folder 26)
    - Jewish Daily Forward, 1957-1967 (Box 231, Folder 27-31)
    - Jewish Labor Bund, 1957-1961 (Box 231, Folder 32)
    - Jewish Labor Committee: Convention, Nov 1967 (Box 231, Folder 33)
    - Jewish Labor Committee: Twenty-Fifth Anniversary, 1959 (Box 231, Folder 34)
    - Jewish Socialist Farband, 1961-1967 (Box 231, Folder 35)
    - Jubilee Journal, 1959-1960 (Box 231, Folder 36)
    - Kabakow, Bernard, 1962-1965 (Box 231, Folder 37)
    - Kaczka, Itche, 1957-1959 (Box 231, Folder 38)
    - Kansas City, MO, 1957-1966 (Box 231, Folder 39)
    - Kaufman, Nusen, 1957-1961 (Box 231, Folder 40)
    - Kissiel, M. (Sarah Reisen), 1965-1968 (Box 231, Folder 41)
    - Kleczewski, Jochenen, 1959-1960 (Box 231, Folder 42)
    - Klog, Ruth, 1960-1962 (Box 231, Folder 43)
    - Kowner, Helena, 1958-1959 (Box 231, Folder 44)
    - Kozil, Andrzej Jan, 1964-1965 (Box 231, Folder 45)
    - Kusiner, Dov and Lilly, 1962-1963 (Box 231, Folder 46)
    - Kwiat, Melech, 1963 (Box 231, Folder 47)
    - Labor Day Greetings, 1967 (Box 231, Folder 48)
    - Landesman, 1961 (Box 231, Folder 49)
    - Landsmanshaften, 1956-1966 (Box 232, Folder 1-3)
    - Landsmanshaften: Lists, Undated (Box 232, Folder 4)
    - Laufer, Shoshana, 1960-1964 (Box 232, Folder 5)
    - League for Mutual Aid, 1963-1966 (Box 232, Folder 6)
    - Leivik, H., Undated (Box 232, Folder 7)
    - Letters of Appreciation, 1948-1949; 1 folder (Box 492)
    - Letters of Appreciation, 1954-1967 (Box 232, Folder 9-12)
    - Levittown, undated (Box 232, Folder 13)
    - Lewin, Reisele, 1957-1958 (Box 232, Folder 14)
    - Liberman, Joseph, 1964 (Box 232, Folder 15)
    - Libo, Alexander, Dr., 1957-1961 (Box 232, Folder 16)
    - Loans, 1962 (Box 232, Folder 17)
    - Location Service, 1966 (Box 232, Folder 18)
    - Los Angeles, CA, 1956-1967 (Box 232, Folder 19-23)
    - Lynn, MA, 1957-1959 (Box 232, Folder 24)
    - Macs, Edward (Latvia), 1961-1965 (Box 232, Folder 25)
    - Maikovskis, Boleslaw (Latvia), 1966 (Box 232, Folder 26)
    - Malden, MA, 1961 (Box 232, Folder 27)
    - Meany, George, 1957 (Box 232, Folder 28)
    - Memos, 1956-1967 (Box 232, Folder 29-31)
    - Memphis, TN, 1957-1964 (Box 232, Folder 32)
    - Mexico, 1956-1967 (Box 232, Folder 33)
    - Miami Beach, FL, 1956-1966 (Box 232, Folder 34)
    - Milwaukee, WI, 1958-1964 (Box 232, Folder 35)
    - Minkowski, Israel-Jerzy, 1963 (Box 232, Folder 36)
    - Minneapolis, MN, 1956-1961 (Box 232, Folder 37)
    - Miodownik, J., 1957-1958 (Box 232, Folder 38)
    - Montreal, 1957-1967 (Box 232, Folder 39-40)
    - Morewski, Abraham, 1961-1964 (Box 232, Folder 41)
    - Mukatel-Tencer, Simone, 1961 (Box 232, Folder 42)
    - Nadel, Benjamin, Undated (Box 232, Folder 43)
    - Nadel, Ruth, 1958 (Box 232, Folder 44)
    - National Community Relations Advisory Council, Undated (Box 232, Folder 45)
    - National Council of Jewish Women, Undated (Box 232, Folder 46)
    - Nazi War Criminals, 1965 (Box 232, Folder 47)
    - New American Project, circa 1959 (Box 232, Folder 48)
    - New Haven, CT, 1958-1967 (Box 232, Folder 49)
    - New Jersey, 1957-1961 (Box 232, Folder 50)
    - New Mexico, 1958 (Box 232, Folder 51)
    - New Orleans, LA, 1957-1963 (Box 232, Folder 52)
    - New York Association for New Americans, 1958-1963 (Box 232, Folder 53)
    - Nicaragua, 1957-1959 (Box 232, Folder 54)
    - Nidebor, M. (Case in Poland), 1955-1959 (Box 233, Folder 1)
    - Norfolk, VA, 1959 (Box 233, Folder 2)